ISABEL YOUNGS

izzyoungs@gmail.com | izzy-youngs.com | (775) 420-1217 | Washington, DC

SUMMARY:

Izzy is currently a Research Specialist at the Georgetown Massive Data Institute, where she collaborates in the development and execution of research projects and public sector collaborations exploring emerging technologies and trends in public policy. Izzy is an experienced professional in policy and data analysis with an interest in delivering consulting and research services to clients.

EDUCATION:

Georgetown University, Washington, DC

M.P.S. (M.Prof) summa cum laude in Urban and Regional Planning, August 2021 Concentrations: Housing policy, data analysis, spatial analysis, quantitative methods

University of Nevada, Reno

B.A. cum laude in Political Science and Communication Studies, Fall 2016

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

Georgetown University, Massive Data Institute, Washington, DC

Research Specialist, August 2021 - Present

- Translates and presents high-level research findings and policy recommendations to funders, stakeholders, and the public through compelling seminars, blogs, reports, infographics, and presentations.
- Conducts research on place-based indicators, population measurement modeling, ethical data governance, and administrative data linkage.
- Creates interactive and data-driven dashboard visualizations utilizing Esri and Tableau to inform data users on the utility and issues with various administrative data sources, primarily census data products.

Georgetown University, Massive Data Institute, Washington, DC

Project Manager, October 2019 - August 2021

- Served as an effective project and product manager across several programs, assisting Principal Investigators in completing grant proposals, developing budgets, and outlining work plans for deliverables.
- Reviewed applications, hired, onboarded, and supervised over one dozen research assistants for the unit and coached them on how to contribute to tasks that aligned with their interests, connecting them to growth opportunities relevant to their research interests.
- Coordinated program operations, performed project and product management tasks, and developed standard operating procedures (SOPs) and documentation in support of MDI's overall strategic plan.
- Monitored the staffing and financial components of research projects in a multi-million-dollar project portfolio to meet contractual and reporting requirements by various public and private funding entities.

Georgetown University, Global Cities Initiative, Washington, DC

Graduate Fellow, January 2021 - June 2021

- Developed an ArcGIS Urban model of the Friendship Heights area to simulate development proposals.
- Performed a conditions assessment to identify market opportunities for Georgetown to expand their spatial analysis footprint.
- Authored a report on the obstacles and opportunities for expanding the use of GIS across the Georgetown ecosystem based on conditions assessment and stakeholder engagement.

Georgetown Business Improvement District, Washington, DC

Data Science Intern, May 2020 - July 2020

- Analyzed location, demographic, and business data from proprietary and open data sources to assess the BID's retail and office market performance as well as visitor and local resident transportation behavior.
- Automated the collection and visualization of bikeshare utilization data which leveraged the Capital Bikeshare API endpoints and referenced the results into a Tableau dashboard.
- Designed, built, and launched Tableau dashboards to assess and visualize major financial trends in the Georgetown BID to contribute to economic development and COVID-19 recovery approaches.

Urban Institute, Office of Technology and Data Science, Washington, DC Academic Intern. January 2020 – May 2020

- Conducted a field scan to synthesize case studies and scientific literature for a report on equity promises and Smart City technology programs in public administration.
- Wrote dozens of briefs on various Smart City and equity initiatives around the country, comparing how
 public procurement and administration practices affected equity promises.
- Contributed to the development of a bias assessment tool by using R to spatially join points and polygons to census tracts, which automatically generates reports on the demographic bias of data sets.

The Lockard Group, Carson City, NV

Legislative Assistant, February 2019 - June 2019

- Developed and carried out a legislative agenda by lobbying state lawmakers, analyzing legislation, suggesting amendments, providing testimony, tracking bills, and writing reports.
- Built a broad legislative coalition through strategic partnerships to advance the legislative priorities of clients, including hospital worker protections, eviction record sealing, affordable housing development streamlining, a low-income housing database, tenant protection laws, and legislation increasing state contributions to the Low-Income Housing Tax Credit fund.

Truckee Meadows Regional Planning Agency, Reno, NV

Intern. January 2019 - June 2019

- Analyzed and prepared revisions for the Truckee Meadows Regional Plan update's draft policies to translate a regional vision into specific, actionable, and measurable policies related to population growth, regional form, public facilities and services, natural resources, and regional coordination.
- Administered and preserved the administrative record of Regional Planning Governing Board and Regional Planning Commission meetings, producing complete and accurate documentation in transcribed minute reports.

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

- Spatial analysis and automation using ArcGIS Pro and R (sf framework)
- Data visualization and cartography with Tableau, Mapbox, ArcGIS Pro, QGIS, and R (ggplot2)
- Programming in web-based environments such as Google Cloud Platform, Colab, and Jupyter Notebook
- Data wrangling and analysis with R (tidyverse framework)
- Web design and documentation with RMarkdown, HTML/CSS, WordPress, and Google Sites
- 3D modeling in Sketchup and ArcGIS Urban